Ed Millington

Location: Vancouver, BC Phone: (+1)236 992 9826 Email: mail@edmill.co.uk

Github: *qithub.com/mllnqtn* Web: *edmill.co.uk*

Profile

Hi! My name's Ed and I'm a senior front-end developer based in Vancouver, British Columbia. I love to build websites and apps that are **beautiful**, **fast**, **accessible** and **standards-compliant**. I have been a professional developer since 2012, having originally come into the field via a background in music and interactive art.

I believe that a front-end developer should always seek to advocate on behalf of the end user, prioritising elegant UI and intuitive UX solutions and ensuring that releases are usable on all devices, from screen-reader equipped desktops to mobile phones with spotty data connections, and everything in between.

I moved from New Zealand to Canada in December 2022. During my time here, I have worked part-time as a freelancer while also raising my daughter, who was born in March 2022. I'm now looking for a new, full-time challenge at a company which will allow me to utilise my existing expertise in an environment of continued technological and process improvement.

Skills

Primary skills:

HTML & CSS / SASS

JavaScript

Vue

React / React Native

Git

Favourite Tools:

Vite / Parcel

Gulp

Docker

VoiceOver

Experience of working with:

RESTful APIs

GraphQL

PHP for Wordpress / Silverstripe

Adobe Photoshop & XD

Node.js and npm

Core methodologies:

BEM

Functional JS

Agile development

DRY code

Work Experience

2016 - 2022

Senior front-end developer: TimeZoneOne, Christchurch NZ

timezoneone.com

TimeZoneOne is a full-service digital agency with offices in Chicago, IL and Christchurch, NZ. I joined the company as an intermediate developer in 2016, progressing to senior level in 2019. During my there, I:

- Collaborated as part of a cross-discipline team, developing and maintaining web and hybrid apps for a broad range of clients.
- Implemented best practices for accessibility: a number of our clients were funded by the US government, and so were required to hit AA WCAG compliance as a minimum.
- Was involved with clients at all stages of the product life-cycle, including on-going maintenance.
- Led initiatives to continually update our coding best-practice. In 2022, I led development of an update to the agency's in-house boilerplate for web projects. This update:
 - increased our indicative mobile performance score on Lighthouse from 40 to 93
 - increased our indicative accessibility score from 72 to 100
 - decreased our generated CSS by 75%
 - decreased our generated JS by 50%
 - replaced monolithic, render-blocking downloads with tree-shaken dynamic imports

2015 - 2016

Web developer & digital designer: Intohand, Bath UK

Intohand was a digital agency which primarily built mobile and tablet apps for enterprise clients. I designed, built & maintained the CMS and storefront websites which accompanied these apps, as well being involved in the design of the UI and UX of the apps themselves.

2012 - 2015

E-book developer: MACK Books, London UK

MACK Books is an independent publishing house, specialising in art and photography. I designed and built enhanced e-books for artists, curators and museums.

mackbooks.co.uk

Education

2012	University of Glamorgan	PGCert: Programming for the web, handheld devices and new media [distinction]
2011	Royal Welsh College of Music & Drama	MMus: Creative Music Technology [distinction]
2007	Durham University	BA (Hons): Classical Past [1st]